偷  天  陷  阱
(纽约市-千禧年前16天)
(降落距离)
(搜寻密码)
(系统关闭)
(康瑞  吉隆坡  马来西亚)
(系统启动)
(吉隆坡  千禧年前15天)
喂？
Hello？
阿明!  把烂音乐关掉!
Ming! Turn that stinking music down!
是你啊
Oh, it's you!
我的画呢？我想要我的画
Where's my painting？I want my painting.
邮寄途中？真有一套
In the mail？Well, that's original!
我很讶异你能办到
I have to say, I'm astonished that you could do it!
身手如此矫健
The climb! All that schlepping at your tender age!
坏消息  眼镜涨价了
Anyway, bad news. The price for the goggles went up.
那幅画不够抵消
The Rembrandt's not gonna cover my expenses.
再加四千万元
Under the circumstances, 40 million would be a bargain.
管他钱从哪来  快去筹钱
I don't care how you get it. Just make sure that you get it fast.
滴答  滴答
Tick-tock... tick-tock.
(卫立保险公司  纽约)
(同一天)
-早上好  -早上好
- Morning, Mr Cruz. - Morning.
艺术品
First you insure the art,
投保一个月就失窃
only to watch it get clipped a month after the client buys it.
不错的广告词
Well, it could become part of our ad campaign.
这会害我
I'll remember that when I go upstairs
被调到西班牙
to hear about my new position in the Toledo office.
我凌晨打电话给你
I called you at 4.30 this morning.
我在家睡觉
I was home in bed.
-你没接电话  -不想接
- You didn't pick up. - I didn't wanna pick up.
有人作伴？
You had company.
-由窗户潜入  -多浪漫
- He came in the window. - How romantic.
我是指窃贼
I think that's how he got in.
70层建筑  厚重的帷幕
This was 70 storeys up with smart-glass windows at 400 pounds a pop.
他用特殊工具
He rigged something.
我猜是
And I think it was...
-自动升降机  -  何以见得？
- telescoping bolts. - And you know this how？
抱歉
Excuse me.
毛主席说：百花齐放
-你真爱出现  -百花齐放
- You're showing off again. - Let a thousand flowers bloom.
-毛主席说的  -没错
- Chairman Mao. - You got it.
他进入后没关窗
He left the window open when he came in.
花吹弯了
The draught blew over the flowers.
窗上一定有升降机的痕迹
I'll bet the bolts on that window have fresh scratches.
-是谁干的？-猜？
- And who do we like for this？- Guess.
又是他
Oh, gee. I wonder.
听我解释
Indulge me.
解释？
Indulge you？
-借用一下？-哦  当然
- Bob, may I？- Oh, yeah, sure. Go ahead.
一个月前这幅画卖出
Four weeks ago, when our client bought the Rembrandt.
-有眼熟的？-没有
- See anyone we know？- No.
没有人察觉
No, and neither did anyone else.
再仔细看
Now look again.
他盯上买主
You think he marked the buyer at the auction house.
-是啊  -认真工作
- Right. - Good work, Bob.
注意他的手法
And let's not forget the calling card.
留下猫王画像
Elvis has not left the building.
麦克一贯作风
This is classic Mac, Hector.
5年来
In the five years I've known you,
你的矛头都指向麦克
you've liked MacDougal for half the cases we've worked.
-他是神偷  -他60岁
- He's the best. - He's also 60 years old.
不再是蜘蛛人
He ain't Spiderman any more.
他很有钱不必去偷画
He's a rich guy. He doesn't have to steal a Rembrandt.
他行窃不是为了钱
You think he steals because he has to？
继续查
Keep working.
你7点
So you get in here at 7am,
工作到晚上10点  自己吃午餐  没有朋友
you work until 10, eat lunch alone, you have no friends at the office...
-观察入微  -我担心你
- Wow, you've been paying attention. - I'm worried about you.
我喜欢孤独  忘记旧情人
Maybe I like being alone. Maybe I'm getting over someone.
有了新人能忘记旧人
Well, they say nothing gets you over the last one like the next one.
你在追求我？
Is this your way of asking me out, Hector？Huh？
只要你不拒绝
Well, um... not if you gonna say no.
你也许对
You may be right.
-他待了一星期  -今早飞回伦敦？
- He was here this week. - He flew back to London this morning？
我可能会派人去查
It might be worth sending someone over there, see what he's up to.
-我了解他  -你？
- I know this guy. - Do you？
对
Sure!
我在调查局时同事曾追捕他
Some years back, when I was at the Bureau, we sent two guys after him.
我知道  他们失踪了
I know, I know. They disappeared. I know the story.
-他们是好探员  -他们是男人
- And these were both good agents. - They were both men.
你拿什么做饵？
What do you have in mind for bait？
-他一定想得到  -不选蒙娜丽莎？
- The one thing I know he wants. - Why not the Mona Lisa？
具挑战性
Our guy likes a challenge.
派我去
Come on.
枪要选我
I want this back.
(来自中国-面具)
(英国  伦敦)
(千禧年前14天)
谢谢  先生
Thank you, sir.
(千禧年科技)
天啊!
God!
可恶!
Shit!
第一条戒律...
Rule number one:
别带枪  带了枪就会用
Never carry a gun, or you might be tempted to use it.
-你来干什么？-问些问题
- Why are you here？- To ask some questions.
说谎就把你丢下楼
If I don't like your answers, you're going out the window.
-为何跟踪我？-想找你合作
- Why are you following me？- I've got a proposition for you.
-你可能是警察  -你只好信任我
- How do I know that you're not a cop？- You'll just have to trust me.
第二条戒律...别信任裸体女人
Rule number two: Never trust a naked woman.
我没衣服穿  被偷了
I had nothing to sleep in. Somebody stole my luggage.
是吗  真想不到
Really？I'm shocked.
这年头贼什么都偷
It's amazing what gets stolen these days. Your bags...
林布兰的画
That Rembrandt.
对  那幅画
Indeed. That Rembrandt.
-这就是你说的？-对
- And this is your proposition？- Yep.
-这是非卖品  -所以用偷的
- I don't think it's for sale. - It's not. I'm gonna steal it.
贝德福宫  警卫森严
From Bedford Palace？It's rather well guarded.
密码每天更换
By its own random-access security code,
但我有密码
changed daily, to which I have the key.
-很好  -要你协助
- Well, good for you. - But I need your help.
我自己办不到
I can't get in and out.
我已找到买主出价4千万
I've already got a buyer who'll give me 40 million for it.
没必要相信你的话
I have no reason to believe a word you've told me.
-但你相信  -为什么？
- But you want to. - Why is that？
你想得到面具
Because you want the mask.
通过考验再谈信任
First we try, then we trust.
意思是？
Meaning what？
明早9点旅馆外见  要穿衣服
Meet me outside the hotel, 9am. Preferably dressed.
你不现身呢？
How do I know you'll be there？
我说话算话  从不迟到
Oh, I'll be there. And I'm never late.
-从不？-从不
- Not ever？- Never.
若迟到...表示我死了
If I'm late... it's because I'm dead.
谁的旅馆外面？
Whose hotel？Yours or mine？
麦克
Mac？
(赫斯古董店)
到了
Ah, here we are.
你进去找赫斯
You go straight in there and ask for Haas.
-赫斯？-人不错
- Haas？- Lovely fella.
性情温和
Very low-key.
你就说要买清朝花瓶  售价20万
You tell him you want to buy a Qing vase. The price is 200,000,
-但你不需付钱  -为什么？
- which, of course, you won't pay. - Why not？
用偷的  你不是贼吗？
Because you're going to steal it. You are a thief, aren't you？
这是张假的信用卡
Take this card, which is fake.
他刷卡时你偷走花瓶
As he turns to swipe it, you swipe the vase.
好
OK.
尽情玩  我等你
Enjoy. I'll be waiting.
-哦!  -抱歉!
- Ooh! - Sorry!
-你好  -嗨
- Hello! - Hi.
-我要买清朝花瓶  -我不认识你
- I'm here for the Qing vase. - I don't know you.
没错  麦克派我来
We've never met before. Mac sent me.
-钱呢？-花瓶呢？
- Where's the money？- Where's the vase？
-这是赝品  -相信我...
- OK, show me the real one. - No, trust me, babe.
这比真品值钱  20万
This is better than a real one. 200,000.
-那是什么？-信用卡
- What's that？- It's a credit card.
对  然后呢？
Yeah. And？
刷卡换机票
I need the miles.
你以为这是什么？
What exactly... do you think this is？
-百货公司？-不  百货公司没老鼠
- Harrods？- No, I've never seen rats at Harrods.
你爱说笑？
You like a joke, don't you？
对
Sure.
这个好笑吗？
How funny is this？
抱歉  我一定弄错了
I'm sorry. I made a terrible mistake about the vase.
很好
Too right.
没错
Uh, yeah, I did.
(千禧虫是撒旦的阴谋)
(13天后世界末日)
没时间了  信主得永生
Time's running out. You can still escape if you'e quick.
听我说...
Now listen.
-花瓶呢？-我砸了
- Where's the vase？- I broke it.
-什么？-抱歉
- What! - I'm sorry...
天啊!
Oh, God!
神保佑
God bless!
他拿着刀  我能怎么办？
The man had a knife. What was I supposed to do？
你要拿到花瓶
You were supposed to get the damn vase!
廉价花瓶  你不会要的
It was a cheap Victorian knockoff!
你没通过考验
You missed the point of the entire exercise.
通过了
No, I didn't.
很好
Oh. Good.
Good girl!
-给我  -是什么？
- Give it to me. - What is it？
给我
Give it to me!
是什么
What is it？!
贝德福宫
Bedford Palace.
详细的平面图  安全系统
The complete plans, security system, soup to nuts.
好车被你糟蹋了
Man, look what you've done to this beautiful car!
还好不是我的  衣服拿去
Yeah, thank God it's not mine. Here, some clothes.
去哪？我的衣服!
Where are we going？These are my clothes!
对  质料不错
Yes, you have some nice things.
-是你吗？偷了我的行李？-我是贼  去告我
- It was you？You stole my luggage？- I'm a thief. So sue me.
-去哪里？-顶楼
- And where are we going？- Up.
-麦克  我的皮箱呢？-在旅馆警卫室
- Mac, where is my suitcase？- It's with hotel security.
什么？
With what？
为什么？
Why？
昨天科技公司发生窃案
Well, there was a robbery yesterday at Cryptonic.
五个超级芯片原型遭窃  各值4百万元
And someone stole five prototype super chips worth $4 million each.
其中之一在你皮箱里
And one of these chips is inside your suitcase.
-在警卫室里  -对
- With hotel security. - Yes.
我还打了通匿名电话  附照片
And one anonymous phone call, from me, plus the photos...
-什么照片？-对了
- What photos？- Oh, yes.
这些
These.
谁拍的...
Who took...？
嘿
Hey!
-这是诱捕  -什么？
- This is entrapment! - What？
-这叫做诱捕  -不  这叫勒索
- This is called entrapment! - Actually, it's called blackmail.
诱捕...
Entrapment...
是警察对小偷
is what cops do to thieves.
要上来？
You coming？
快到了
Almost there.
没锁？没警卫？
No lock？No security？
没动歪脑筋吧？
You're not casing the joint already, are you？
这里走
This way.
哦  哇
Oh, wow!
请进
Shall we？
我的天
Oh, my God.
-收藏真不少  -谢谢
- This is quite a collection. - Thank you.
都是同时期艺品？
Only contemporary art？
-很讶异？-不  只是没料到
- You sound surprised. - No, it's just not what I expected.
我以为有盔甲与宝剑
Where are the suits of armour and crossed swords？
在阁楼  威士忌？
Up in the attic. Whiskey？
好啊  谢谢
Sure. I'd love one.
哇
Wow!
都是用钱买的？
Is all this paid for？
-用血汗  -敬面具
- With blood. Cheers. - To the mask.
-带你去房间  -曾带谁去过？
- I'll show you to your room. - Who else do you bring here？
没有
No-one.
-真悲哀  -为什么？
- That's sad. - Why？
有艺术品却无人分享
Well, to have something like this and not share it with anyone.
不需要分享
I don't need to share it with anyone.
很多人收藏为了炫耀
Most people buy art to show it off.
我不是
I collect art for me.
房间在这里
Your room's this way.
晚安
Good night, then.
-还很早  -明天要早起
- But it's still early. - Yes, we have an early start.
我还不累
But I'm not tired!
你睡哪里？
Where do you sleep？
干嘛？
Why？
以免不时之需
Just in case I need anything.
-能问你个问题？-当然
- May I ask you something？- Sure.
有你无法操控  诱惑的人？
Has there ever been anyone you couldn't manipulate, beguile, or seduce？
没有
No.
我令你不自在？
Why, do I make you uneasy, Mac？
不  不会
No. No, not at all.
事实上  我想现在或许
In fact, I think now might
这是个好机会谈一谈
be a good time for you and I to, uh... discuss something.
谈什么？
Well, what do you have in mind？
规矩
The rules.
好
Oh! OK.
为了让个贼互相信任...
In order for there to be complete trust between thieves,
不能牵扯感情
there can be nothing personal.
工作归工作  各尽其责
A job is a job. You do your part, I do mine.
若有人做非分之想
If one of us thinks about something other than the task at hand,
会导致被捕或送命
we'll either both get caught, or both get dead.
晚安
Good night again.
不
No...
Nope. No...
不
No. No.
Nope.
-由这里进入  -那是湖
- That's the way in. - That's the lake.
我知道  公爵
Yes, I know it's the lake, dear. The first duke
为情妇挖的隧道
dug a tunnel as a back door for his mistress.
百年后改建成湖
100 years later, they flooded the place.
我们潜水进去
OK, so we go underwater.
我潜水  我偷面具  你分一成利润
I go underwater. I steal the mask. You get a finder's fee of 10%.
但我有密码
But I have the code to the mask case, dear.
现在告诉我
Which you're now going to give to me.
不要
No!
-你浪费我的时间？-你浪费我的时间？
- Have you been wasting my time？- Have you been wasting mine？
我安排你回伦敦
I'll arrange your return to London.
我不是你所想的
I'm not who you think I am, Mac.
最好不是
I hope not, for your sake.
我是贼
I'm a thief.
你常挂在嘴边
So you keep telling me.
我偷了那幅画
I stole the Rembrandt.
-麦克  我偷了那幅画  -我是米开朗基罗
- Mac, I stole the Rembrandt! - And I painted the Sistine Chapel!
问我怎么偷的
Come on! Ask me how I did it!
- 怎么偷的？ - 我从屋顶...
- How did you do it？- I came in from the roof.
用升降索下20层楼
I dropped 20 floors down on a McNeal Descender.
-必须是攀爬高手  -没错
- You must be a hell of a climber. - I am.
嗯？
Mm？
我是攀爬高手
I am a hell of a climber!
我是...杰出的...攀爬高手
I am... one... hell of a climber.
画怎么带出去？
But how did you get it out of there？
那...
Now that...
就是最了不起
is the most...
的部分
beautiful part!
-邮寄出去  -不!
- I mailed it. - No!
丢进大楼邮筒
I put it down their own mail chute.
简单
Simple...
有效率...安全
effective... safe.
很聪明
That's very clever.
不  不是聪明
Nope. Not clever.
是完美
It was perfect!
太厉害了
Absolutely unbelievable!
对  很美的画
You're right. It is beautiful.
可知林布兰
Did you know that Rembrandt
长年与父母同住？
lived with his parents well into his forties？
你一定知道  你完美无缺
But of course you'd know that. You're perfect.
怎么在你手上？
How did you get that？
何必去阁楼...邮务室在一楼
Why rob the penthouse... when the mailroom's on the ground floor？
怎么知道是我？
How did you know I took it？
能制作那些装备的人不多
There's only a handful of people who can make the equipment you used.
我都认识
And I know all of them.
-买主在等  -对
- Someone was expecting that. - Obviously.
-吉隆坡的康瑞先生  -天啊
- Mr Conrad Greene of Kuala Lumpur. - Oh, God...!
是订金？或交换条件？
What was it？A down payment？A service this Mr Greene is providing？
类似的
Yeah, something like that.
马来西亚有什么好偷的？
What could you possibly want to steal in Malaysia？
-嗯？-1亿现金
- Hm？- A hundred million dollars.
偷什么？
What's the job？
智者说...
Like the wise man said:
通过考验再谈信任
First we try, then we trust.
早安
Ah, good morning.
我的车怎么撞得面目全非？
Wanna tell me why my Jaguar looks like you drove it off a fuckin' cliff？
堤贝多  很抱歉
Thibadeaux, I'm awfully sorry.
-你欠我14万元  -用4千万的面具交换？
- You owe me 140 G's. - How about a $40 million Chinese mask？
有涡轮传动与音响？
Is it turbocharged with a six-CD changer？
装备齐全了？
Did you get everything I need？
买新车还我
When we done, you buyin' me a new car.
没问题  有小型气垫？
Agreed. Did you get the small pneumatics？
小型气垫  只能给侏儒用
Yeah, I got the small pneumatics. You gotta be a damn elf to use 'em.
-炸药？-在车里
- The det cord？- It's in the van.
威力强大
That's some nasty shit.
最好当心
Don't mix it with nothing else or you'll be all over the floor.
-这是啥？-红外线热导相机
- What the hell's this？- IR thermo- camera, what you asked for.
我说过不要液晶屏幕
I specifically said no liquid-plasma screen.
只买得到这种
That was specifically all I could get.
怎么办？不是我要的
How can I do this without the right tools？
拜托  你以为随处买得到？
Gimme a break, man. You think I go to K- Mart and get this shit？
自己想办法
Figure out something. You always do.
-美人呢？-在湖边  受训
- Where's the honey？- In the loch, training.
我说我游一小时  她得加倍
I told her I swim for an hour every day, so she'll do it for two.
什么时候行动？
So, when is it we do the dirty？
再等一下
Maybe we should wait a bit.
她有更大的目标
She's got a bigger job after this one.
这个够大了
This is big enough, man.
有更大的
It's never big enough.
-你不会爱上她吧？-不会
- You are keepin' this strictly business, right？- Strictly.
替女人买过衣服？
Have you ever bought a woman's dress？
为了任务
It's for the job. For her.
我不知道尺寸
I don't know her size.
她应该穿6号
Well, I'd say she's probably a six, but
穿4号更合身
she'd look real fine in a four.
我有个女友说女人靠衣装
I had this girl, Tina. She said the dress made the woman.
我说身材才重要
I say the woman makes the dress.
有意思
That's a lovely story.
弄得到衣服？
But could you get the dress？
这么大把年纪
Mac, you're too old for this shit.
面具最好值得
This mask thing better be worth it.
值得
Oh, it is.
我是指对我而言
It better be worth it for me.
装备运来了
Our gear has arrived.
谁运来的？
Who brought it？
送货的
Delivery man.
邮购买这些装备？
You order this stuff from a catalogue？
不  跟熟人订购的
No, I order it from someone I trust implicitly.
装备不少  帮个忙
There's lots more, if you'e not too tired.
往左一点  往左  距离？
Left a bit. Left a bit. What is it？
-15  -很好
- It's 15. - Good. Now...
退后  继续拉  退后
Straight back, straight back. Go on, take it out. Back.
对  退后  拉紧  紧一点
There you go. There. Yeah, straight back now. Keep it taut. Taut!
对了...终于
There. That's it. Ah, finally!
很好
Good. Well done.
3...
Three...
2...
two...
-5分贝  -还是太大声
- Five decibels. - Still too loud.
好了？
Set？
-1...  -砰
- One and... - Bang.
-2...  -砰
- Two and... - Bang.
-3...  -砰
- Three and... - Bang.
4...
Four and...
喔!  砰
Oh, yeah. Bang.
-砰要跟钟声吻合  -好  我忘了
- The bangs must be with the clock's chimes! - OK, I forgot, I forgot!
再一次
Again.
腿并拢  蹲伏钻入
Knees together. Down, down, tuck.
我顾着面具  你专心通过
I'll watch the mask. You keep your mind on your movement.
伸
Reach!
不  这些是红外线
No, no, no! These are the lasers! Hm？
我当你的眼睛  你闭上眼
I am your eyes. So you keep yours closed, because you can't see.
我会在屏幕监看
But I'll be watching every move on our screen.
快  你只有3分钟
Come on, move! You have three minutes till the guard gets here!
上  很好
Up... Good!
左脚伸
Better. Left leg. Left!
又碰到
There you...
我要休息
I need a break!
做对了就能休息
You'll get a break... when you get it right!
从头开始
Number one!
2...
Two and...
-砰  -3...
- Bang. - Three and...
-砰  -4...
- Bang. - Four and...
-砰  -5...充气
- Bang. - Five and... inflate!
怎么回事？超过一秒钟
Well, what's this？It's supposed to be one second!
阀门没全开
You're supposed to open the valve full!
开了!不信自己看
I did open it full! Look, it's open!
好  我待会调整
All right, very well! I'll rectify it later. Hm？
6...
Six.
杠杆  7...掉下
Lever. Seven. Drop.
-8...  -泄气
- Eight. - Deflate.
很好
Well done!
我全开了!不信去看!
I did open it full, OK？You can go over there and check.
快一点
Come on!
看...
Here...
我从那里进去
This is where I'm gonna enter into them.
到第一道红外线  最难的
Then I'll come up through the first beam. The hardest part.
你看  这里
I'm just gonna... You see？Right here.
安全通过第一道红外线
Once I get under the first beam, I'll be fine.
就过关了
So don't worry about me, OK？
计算机仿真很有帮助
Once I have this on the computer,
蒙上眼都能过
I can visualise it. I can do this blindfolded now.
真的？
Really？
-有必要吗？-是的
- Is this absolutely necessary？- Yes.
-你看不到  -而你看得到
- Because you won't be able to see them... - And you will. Right.
信任我
Trust me.
准备好了
We're ready!
这由我决定
I'll tell you when we're ready.
你忘了压力钮
You forgot the damn pressure switch, didn't you？
你就是情不自禁
Jesus! You just can't help it, can you？
-什么？-惹人厌的浑蛋
- Help what？- Being such a nasty son of a bitch.
这是必须的
This is how it has to be.
-你受不了...  -麦克  鬼扯!
- But if you can't deal with it... - Hey, Mac？Bullshit!
你只是不敢对我好
You know what？I think you're just afraid to be nice to me!
混蛋
Bastard!
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas!
-给我的？-我用不上
- For me？- Well, it's certainly not for me.
打开看看
Open it.
我猜你穿6号  但4号更合身
I thought you were probably a six, but would look very nice as a four.
很漂亮
It's beautiful.
但是...
But？
从没有人送我衣服
Believe it or not, no-one's ever bought me a dress before.
是用你的钱买的
Well, it comes out of your share.
我没礼物送你
I didn't get you anything.
-不必了  -不  我要送
- Not necessary. - No, no. I want to.
马上回来
I won't be long.
我等你
I'll be waiting!
卫立保险公司
Waverly lnsurance.
嗨  这里是贝克  库兹在另一条线
Hi, this is Virginia Baker. Hector Cruz on a secure line, please.
我不是叫你每天向我报告吗？
Didn't I say something about checking in every day？
抱歉  行动电话不通
I'm sorry, Hector, but I can't just pick up my cellphone here.
我很担心  你在哪里？
I've been worried about you. Where are you？
在麦克的城堡里
I'm staying with Mac, at his castle.
说详细点  他上钩了？
Spare me the details. Did he take the bait？
是的  他抓住了林布兰
Yeah, big time. And he got the Rembrandt.
上钩了
Well...!
中大奖了
Tilt bingo jackpot!
现在抓他？
You wanna pick him up now？
画在他手上  他预谋...
We've got him for possession, conspiracy...
我在他作案时抓住他
But I can catch him with his hand in the till.
-当场逮到能判25年徒刑  -你办得到？
- Grand larceny, 25years to life. - You think you'e up to that？
-绝对可以  -告诉我时间地点
- Hector, I know so. - So give me the how and the when.
-我知道就通知你  -一言为定？
- Look, I'll call you as soon as I know, OK？- Is that a promise？
一言为定  我得走了
Course it's a promise. Look, I gotta go.
等一下
OK, just wait a second. I wanted to...
你好
Hello？
麦克
Mac!
Mac？
麦克
(上楼)
Mac？
-找到你要的？-哦
- Did you find what you were looking for？- Ohh!
-吓我一跳  -人们说恐惧...
- God, you scared me! - You know what they say about fear.
-能引发潜力  -是吗？
- The only remedy's to cut off the head. - Really？
美丽的景色
Beautiful view, isn't it？
让我头脑更清晰
It helps me to see things more clearly.
我每次都会丢东西下去
You know, I never come up here without dropping something off.
丢啊
Go ahead, then.
2小时后出发
We leave in two hours.
珍
Gin!
如何？
Well？
呃
Well.
我所见过最美丽的贼
You're the most beautiful crook I've ever seen.
多谢夸奖
Why, thank you, kind sir.
玫瑰做记号
So I'll recognise you.
以免我跟错了人回家
I wouldn't wanna go home with the wrong man now, would I？
化装舞会
It is a masked ball.
我们装扮成别人
We all go as someone else.
(贝德福宫)
(千禧年前4天)
(面具  中国艺术品)
10点30...  3...
Ten-thirty in... three...
2...
two...
1  对时
one. Now.
我们去参观面具吧
We should pay our respects to the guest of honour.
走吧
Shall we？
1  2  3  4  5
One, two, three, four, five.
转身
And... north.
1  2  3
One, two, three.
Dum-de-dum, dum-de-dum.
到了
Oh, here we are.
哦
Oh!
15秒
15 seconds.
准备
Going hot.
7  6
Seven... six...
5...
five...
four...
3...2...
three... two...
2...
And two.
3...
And three.
4...
And four.
5...
And five.
6...
Six.
7...
And seven.
8...
And eight.
-加压  -9...
- More air. - Nine.
-加压  -10...
- More. - Ten.
再来!
More!
-11...太大声了  -加压!
- Eleven. It's too loud! - More!
好了
OK.
上去
Up.
很好  你有3分钟
Good. You've got three minutes on the guard.
保持平衡  踮脚
Balance. One point.
抬脚
Now lift.
剩2分钟
Two minutes on the guard.
抬高
Lift.
伸  转
Extend. Now turn.
再抬高一点
Up a little more.
屈膝
Now bend the knee.
剩75秒
75 seconds.
别动
Freeze.
你身体遮住了  我看不到
You're blocking the beam. I can't see it.
交给我办
Got it covered.
真聪明
Clever girl.
记住  要按下压力钮
Now, remember the damn pressure switch!
很好
Good girl.
剩35秒
35 seconds.
解除压力钮装置
Preparing pressure switch neutralisation device.
离开那里  快!
Now get out of there - fast!
太棒了!
Unbelievable!
-面具给我  -拿去
- Let me have the mask. - Here he is!
说实话  否则淹死你
Now this is where we play Truth or Dare.
什么？
What？
老实说...
First we start with truth, huh？
你替卫立保险工作
You work for Hector Cruz at Waverly lnsurance, hm？
没错...
Now,
你最好别说谎
I dare you to lie to me.
-我不懂你说什么  -什么!
- I don't know what you're talking about. - What!
工作是掩护  为得到密码
The job was a cover! That's how I got the code.
不  你两边讨好
No, no, no, you're playing both sides.
将面具卖给康瑞  再出卖我
You're gonna sell the mask to Conrad Greene, then turn me in.
-有更大目标  -没什么目标
- No, I need you for the job. - There is no other job!
有!  那价值...
There is! It's worth over...
别说值上亿
And don't tell me it's worth a hundred million.
对  不是上亿
It's not. It's, it's... You're right, it's not.
是上兆
It's worth over a billion.
你可分得1兆
And that's just your share!
我没骗你
I'm not lying!
没有你我办不到
I can't do this job without you, Mac.
请跟我去吉隆坡
Please come with me to Kuala Lumpur.
麻烦快点决定
Can you just decide soon, please？
4  3
Four, three,
2  1
two, one.
时间到  你说24小时后...
Your time's up. You said you would tell me
告诉我内容
what the next job is in 24 hours.
是银行
It's a bank.
然后呢？
And？
我没说要详述
And I didn't say I'd tell you any more.
这里真漂亮
Isn't it beautiful here？
(吉隆坡  马来西亚)
(千禧年前2天)
我没兴趣抢银行
Banks have never really been my thing.
1兆是大数目
Think a billion dollars and change your mind.
-我不喜欢意外  -相信我  不会的
- I just don't like surprises. - Trust me, there won't be any.
相信我  意外无所不在
Trust me. There always are surprises.
这地方...  真温暖
I must say, it's, uh... very homey.
谢谢
Why, thank you!
我提到的银行...
Of course, when I said bank,
不是普通银行
I didn't mean just any bank.
有窗景的房间
A room with a view!
全球最高建筑...
I give you the world's tallest building.
偷这个？
And we're going to steal it？
国际票据交换银行
Home of the International Clearance Bank,
处理东南亚国家
which I'm sure you know controls
大笔金额交易
all big money transactions in Southeast Asia.
-感兴趣了？-洗耳恭听
- Do I have your attention now？- Undivided.
这是纽约国际票据交换银行
Here, the headquarters of the International Clearance Bank in New York.
提供全球分行计算机
Running from there are hack proof, firewalled, dedicated lines
防黑客系统
to computers in its branch offices around the world.
接达需经纽约控制中心
The only access is from central control in New York
或分行戒备森严的计算机
or from the totally secure computers in the branch offices.
在吉隆坡只有一个人能接达
In Kuala Lumpur, only one man has unlimited access.
李坤鸿  吉隆坡票据交换银行总裁
Lee Kuan Hong, Chairman of the International Clearance Bank of Kuala Lumpur.
需通过两道关卡
Vaults are accessed by two things:
密码及视网膜扫瞄
a key code and a completely unfakeable retinal scan.
-大家早安  -嗨
- Morning, everyone. Nice day, uh？- Hi.
仿制视网膜
Which we're gonna fake.
此刻总裁
Right now, our Chairman, with a face full of Mace,
正在检查眼睛
is getting his eyes checked,
康瑞的手下正协助进行
with a little help from Conrad Greene's guys,
希望吧
hopefully.
-了解吗？-很了解
- With me so far？- All the way.
千禧虫
Now, because of the millennium bug,
迫使银行进行全面安检
our friends at International Clearance
不断重复演练
will be running integrity tests, which they're rehearsing as we speak.
悉尼测试准备...
Prepare test shutdown for Sydney in...
午夜时
Just before midnight, local time,
关闭中央处理机30秒
they'll shut down the mainframe in each zone for 30 seconds.
-悉尼关闭  -进行测试
- Sydney is shut down. - Run test program.
利用那30秒连接中央处理机
Now we need those 30 seconds to patch into the mainframe.
另外还需
We then need ten seconds of one-on-one time
10秒钟下载
with the computer, to download...
-数据  -如何取得那10秒？
- the stuff. - How do we acquire those ten seconds？
用偷的
We steal 'em.
我在纽约放置
The transmitter I left behind simply
时钟调传输器
overrides the signal of the atomic clock. So,
从明晚11时开始
from 11pm tomorrow night
他们的钟每分钟快1/6秒
their clocks gain a fraction of a second every minute
可偷得10秒钟
and we gain our ten seconds.
下载什么数据？
And what is this stuff we are downloading？
安雅？
Enya？
里面的磁盘花了我5年
Cunningly disguised in there is a disk that took me five years to make,
整天窝在保险公司
cooped up in my broom closet at Waverly lnsurance.
银行计算机将从各账户...
It tells the ICB computer to transfer relatively small amounts of money
转出少量金额存入我的账户
from hundreds of corporations all over Southeast Asia into my account.
-我们的账户  -对  我们的
- Our account. - Yeah, our account.
总共8兆元
Eight billion dollars in total.
你说一兆元
You said one billion.
那是你的份
I said that was your share.
那么多钱何不平分？
What can you do with seven billion that you can't do with four？
刷新纪录
Hold the record.
单独
Alone.
单独很孤独
Sounds rather lonely.
孤独？
Alone？
孤独很好
No. Alone is good.
-要喝啤酒？-谢谢
- You want a beer？- Thank you.
-需要三周时间准备  -什么？
- We'll need three weeks to prepare. - What？
-最少  -明晚一定要行动
- Minimum. - No. It has to be tomorrow night.
办不到
No way.
错过千禧年就没机会了
You don't understand. It has to be millennium midnight or it's never.
只好作罢  办不到
Then it's never. It's impossible.
你...
You...
好  平分
OK. Fifty-fifty.
什么？
What？
你听到了
You heard.
办不到
It's impossible.
但可行
But doable.
各位  高度是海拔700英尺
Ladies and gentlemen, we are now standing over 700ft above sea level.
全球最高最长的空桥
Our sky bridge is the longest and highest in the world.
延伸300英尺连接
It stretches over 300ft to the opposite tower.
由四支钢柱支撑
It is supported, as you can see, by four flexible steel pillars.
这些灯为衬托千禧年派对
The lights are being hung for our millennium party tomorrow.
4万多个灯泡照亮夜空
Over 40,000 light bulbs will make this truly a sight to remember.
(空桥-霹雳小组  感应器)
(输入键  B计划)
这是什么东西？
So, what have we here？
有眼镜和视网膜扫瞄器
We have the goggles with the chairman's retinal scan.
还有进入86层楼时所需的通行证
And we have the chairman's access card to the 86th floor
全都装在袋子里
in the bag.
难道没有别的要告诉我的吗？
Anything else I need to know？
孔夫子说过  别用大炮打蚊子
Confucius, he say: Don't use cannon to kill mosquito.
是啊
Right!
我把我的宝贝给你看了  现在轮到你给我看你的了
Well, now that I've shown you mine, it's your turn to show me yours.
-在这里  -太棒了...
- Well, here she is. - Oh, goody, goody, goody!
拿来给老爹看吧
Bring it to Papa.
真是艺术精品  对吧？名师作品
Oh! A thing of beauty, huh？A joy forever!
面具呢？我的面具呢？
And where's the mask？I want my mask. Come on!
你这一票是和麦克合作的？
Oh! So you're working with MacDougal on this, huh？
没错
Yeah.
嗯
Uh-huh.
你知道我有什么建议吗？
I would suggest that
我建议你该去找你的伙伴好好谈谈
you have a little talk with your partner.
如果他还在国内的话
If he's still in the country.
我看通行证和眼镜暂时不能给你了
In the meantime, I'll hold on to the access card and goggles.
你一定要相信我  我完全不知情...
Conrad, you've gotta believe me. I had no idea.
我发誓我绝对不会这样对你的
I swear to God, I'd never do this to you!
不要...别耍我  你这个小贱人
Don't...! Don't pout at me, you little bitch!
-别这样...  -滚出去...
- Come on, Conrad. - Get out of here! Get out!
快滚  快滚
Get out! Just get out! Get outta here!
看到你我真高兴
Baby, I'm glad to see you!
我要取消这个行动
I'm calling it off.
听好了  我晚点再帮你拿林布兰
You take this. I'll get the Rembrandt for you later.
慢一点  老兄  你在说什么？
What you sayin'？
她陷得太深  不会成功的
She's over her head. It's not happening.
那你们两个另外那票大买卖呢？
What about the big, giant, huge job you were all cute about in Scotland？
你该不会是想要背叛我吧？
Now you wouldn't be tryin' to cut a brother out of anything？
-没什么好背叛的  -坐下
- There's nothing to cut you out of. - Sit down, Mac.
坐下
Sit down.
我叫你给我他妈的坐下
I said, sit the fuck down.
你知道吗  麦克...
You know, Mac,
我想这件事就我们两个来做吧
I think it's time to take your girlfriend out of the equation...
-别再管你的女朋友了  -她不是我的女朋友
- and get down to the you and me of it all. - She's not my girlfriend.
不知怎么地  我忽然觉得
See, I'm gettin' this little Yoko vibe,
你女朋友想要掌控全局
like all of a sudden your girlfriend's the one in control.
如果换拍挡  游戏规则也会变
Now, you change partners, you change the rules.
我们的规则是麦克下手
And the rules are... Mac does the job.
我来把风
I watch Mac's back.
除非有我的许可  否则不能取消行动
You don't call off nothin' unless I say so.
珍...
Gin？
珍
面具在哪里？你这个浑蛋？我信任你
Where is it, you bastard？I trusted you!
-你这个浑蛋...我信任你  -珍
- You bastard! I trusted you! I trusted you! - Gin! Hey! Gin!
面具在哪里？
Where is it？!
你为什么把它拿走？
Why'd you take it？
别装了
Get up! I know you're faking!
你到哪里去了？
Where'd you go？
-你为什么把它拿走？-我本来要把它卖了
- Why'd you take it？- I was going to sell it.
你为什么没有卖呢？
Then why didn't you？
因为...  我下不了手
Because... I... couldn't do it.
为什么？
Why not？
我知道如果我叫你忘了那一票
I knew that if I told you to forget this job,
离开这里
get the hell outta here,
你绝对不会答应的  对不对？
you wouldn't do it, would you？
-嗯？-没错
- Hm？- No.
对
Right.
-你担心我吗  麦克？-是的
- Were you worried about me, Mac？- Well, yes.
-真的？-替我们担心
- Were you？- I was worried about both of us.
别担心
Don't be.
抱歉  忘了规矩
Whoops, sorry. Forgot about the rules.
你曾触犯规矩？
Have you ever broken 'em, Mac？
没有
No.
-一次都没？-没有
- Not once？- No.
从不？
Never？
从不
Never.
孤独很好  不是？
Alone is... good, eh？
不  才怪
No. Bullshit.
我讨厌孤独  糟透了
I hate alone. Alone sucks.
-是吗？-对
- Really？- Yeah.
珍...
Hey... Gin...
珍
Gin...
珍...
Gin.
Mm! Gin!
-珍  -干嘛？
- Gin... Gin. - What!
我目前的状况...
My situation is...
太复杂
so complicated,
我无法...
I can't...
无法解释
I can't explain.
试试看？
Well, can you try？
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我也爱你们
Yeah, I love you, too, guys.
你干嘛？放开我!
Hey! What are you doing! Get off me!
救命!
Help!
海特
Hector...!
你怎么来了？
What are you doing here？
报上登面具遭窃
Oh, I read in the newspapers that the mask thing's gone down.
而你销声匿迹
I don't hear from my trusty agent, so naturally I worry.
我询问医院  陈尸间
I call the hospitals, I call the morgue,
最后询问航空公司
and, finally, I call the airlines.
我亟需最新信息  帮帮忙
I'm a man badly in need of news here, Miss Baker. Help me out.
最新信息？
You want news, Hector？The news is,
你这样会泄漏我的身份
I don't appreciate you blowing my cover like this.
他下一个目标更大...
He's planning a job that's gonna make the mask look like...
你不相信？好  取消调查  逮捕他
You don't believe me？Fine. Then pull me in and pick him up.
为何取消？你们这么亲密
Why would I pull you in when you seem to be getting so close to Mac？
天啊!
Oh, jeez!
-这是工作  -工作？
- This was business, Hector! - Business...
你确定没有隐瞒？
Are you sure there's nothing else you wanna tell me？
再给我一天  保证给你答案
Look, give me until tomorrow. I promise you, you'll have it all.
我能回去工作了？
Can I go back to work now？
别跟丢了
Don't lose her.
她不喜欢那张照片
Guess she didn't appreciate my pictures.
我早就说过...
Did I tell you, or did I tell you？
-她两边通知  -她说是工作
- She's screwin' you both, man. - She says it's business. I believe her.
对  她又去
Yeah, she's probably on her way
找麦克用力做了
to Mr Mac right now to do a little business.
别这样!
Don't do that. You do not do that!
不准这么说!
You do not speak like that! You do not!
宝贝  用不着这么激动
Hector, baby! There ain't no need to get all up and hard, my man!
我说过值回票价
Now I said I'd make this trip worth your while.
最好没错
You better be right.
听堤贝多的准没错
All you gotta do is listen to old Thibadeaux.
(国际票据交换银行)
(千禧年前一小时)
我没这么邋遢过
I've never felt so underdressed in all my life.
对时
Synchronise
现在
now.
好  传输器已连上计算机
OK. The dish should be coming on-line.
从现在开始到午夜
Every minute, from now to midnight, we steal a tenth of a second
我们窃取银行的时间
from our friends at the International Clearance Bank.
(吉隆坡  香港)
他们还在
They're still there.
当心点
So, uh, be careful, OK？
等一下
Wait.
-珍  -不  别说话
- Gin... - No, don't... Don't say a word.
有没有看到...蓝衣服的？
Hey, have you seen a guy in blue overalls？
抱歉  我跟丢了
Four to Base. No, I'm sorry, sir, I lost him.
不知道  下楼梯就不见了
I don't know. Just somewhere between the stairs and the truck. Yeah.
女士
Ma'am.
各位  警察局长杨三
Boys, this is Chief lnspector Yeng San,
保险公司的库斯先生
and Mr Cruz from Waverly lnsurance, New York.
大楼里有两名嫌疑犯
They have a special interest in some guests tonight.
(电梯监控系)
(5号电梯)
(走廊监视器)
电梯口见
Elevator. One minute.
电梯坏了
This one's not working.
换搭另外一台
I'd use that one.
试着面带笑容
Do try to put a smile on your face, dear.
他就是国际窃贼？
So, this is your international art thief, Mr Cruz？
看来不太危险
He doesn't look very dangerous, does he？
等一下
Not yet.
好
OK.
现在
And now...
画面静止
Now time stands still.
希望
Hopefully.
请问...
Excuse me.
-他们去哪了？-在70楼
- Did you see where they went？- 70th floor, sir.
-在看烟火吧  -那里有监视器？
- Watching the fireworks, probably. - Do you have cameras up there？
-有  -找找看好吗？
- Of course. - Would you mind？
(获准通行)
-找不到他们  -什么意思？
- I can't find them, sir. - What do you mean？
就是找不到
Sir, I... I just can't find them.
有2000多个监视器  快找
There are 2,000 cameras in this building! Find them!
我无意干涉  但他们很聪明
Listen, I don't mean to intrude, but these people are very, very smart.
他们是有计划的
If they've disappeared, it's because they mean to.
这里有艺术品？
Is there any art in this building？
不多
Some.
-银行那边呢？-只有一台大计算机
- And the Bank Clearance House？- Nothing but a big computer.
事有蹊跷
Something doesn't smell right.
库斯先生  根据你与调查局所述...
Well, Mr Cruz, on the say-so of you and your friends in the FBl,
我们派出大批警力  你说呢？
I have a lot of men on standby here. What would smell right to you？
逮捕他们
I think you should pick them up.
(走廊监视器)
声波脉冲
Sonic pulse.
持续5毫秒
Five milliseconds.
-双脚放在...  -脉波之间
- Now, put your feet down... - Between the pulses, I know.
好...  3
Now... three,
3  2
two, one.
And...
2...
Two.
3...
Three.
4...
Four.
5...
Five!
6...
Six.
7...
Seven.
8...
Eight.
9  10
Nine... ten.
指纹刷
Fingerprint brush.
打蚊子...
Kill... mosquito...
-大炮...  -别用大炮打蚊子
- Cannon... - Don't use a cannon to kill a mosquito.
-孔子说的  -很厉害
- Confucius. - You are good.
就是这个？钱在哪里？
This is it？Whatever happened to money？
-眼镜给我  -一块钱都没
- Gimme the goggles. - Stuff you can get your hands on.
哦  天啊
Oh, God!
所以我不偷银行
This is why I don't do banks now.
以前有金条  保险箱
There used to be bars of gold, safety-deposit boxes...
花绿绿的钞票呢？
I mean, where's the good old-fashioned loot？
钞票就在...
The loot, my dear,
那里面
is right in there.
剩20秒
20 seconds.
吉隆坡准备关机
Prepare to go off-line in KL in
-5  4  3...  -这不是演习
- five, four, three, - This is for real, people.
2  1  开始
two, one, go.
暂停交易
-纽约提早了10秒  -美国人真性急
- They're ten seconds early. - Why are Americans always in a hurry？
-快了10秒  -FDZ完成
- Ten seconds in. - FDZ complete.
关闭
Clear.
倒数15秒
Approaching... fifteen.
关闭
Clear.
-好了  -关闭
- Here we go! - Clear!
-全关了  -10秒
- All clear. - Ten seconds.
-5  4  3  -三秒
- Five, four, three, - Three seconds, people.
2  1...
two, one...
关闭
We're clear.
马来西亚  新年快乐
Happy New Year, Malaysia!
-10  9  8  -好了
- Ten, nine, eight, - Come on!
9  8...
nine, eight...
7  6...
seven, six,
4...
four
-2  -1
- two, - one.
(完成转帐8兆元)
-成功了!  -  新年快乐
- We did it! - Happy New Year!
千禧年快乐
Happy Millennium!
太完美了
That was perfect.
(系统中断)
(86楼警铃启动)
珍
Ah, Gin...!
磁盘!
The disk!
-拿扳手来  -什么？
- Get me the spanner! - The what？
扳手!
The wrench!
他们发现磁盘就完了
If they find that disk, we're dead!
出口
The door!
我挡不住
I can't stop it, Mac!
霹雳小组  紧急行动
Armed Response Unit, Code Red.
算了  走!
Leave it! Come on!
-5号电梯启动  -谁在里面？
- Elevator five's on the move, sir. - Who's in it？
-空的  -不
- It's empty. - No...
他们还在里面  画面暂停  看
I think they're still in it. Look. They freeze-framed the camera. See？
关闭电源
Shut it down.
意外无所不在
There's always a surprise.
这里
Here.
(49楼  关闭)
嫌犯在50楼附近
Suspects in the vicinity of floor 50.
库斯先生  他们搜翅难飞
OK, Mr Cruz, your friends are rats in a trap.
-往哪？-货用电梯
- Where to？- Service elevators.
快离开!
Get out! Out! Out!
走楼梯
Try the stairs.
回去
Get back!
等一下...
Hang on.
我有好主意
Got a better idea.
麦克  脾气真大
Temper, temper, Mr MacDougal.
嫌犯避开摧泪瓦斯往南逃
Confirm suspects on floor 50, heading south away from the gas.
他们猜不到
They'll think we'll try to avoid the gas,
闭上眼  深呼吸
so keep your eyes closed and take a deep breath.
退后
Get back.
拿去
Here.
-是什么？-B计划
- What's this？- Plan B pack.
-怎么用？-派上用场再告知
- For what？- If we need it, I'll tell you.
到达通风孔就安全了
Now, if we can get across the vent shaft, we should be OK.
在哪里？
Across where？
那里
There.
走
Let's go.
OK.
快!
Move it!
继续走
Keep moving!
快!
Come on!
哦  天啊
Oh, God!
珍!当心!
Gin! Watch out!
珍!快到了!快!
Gin! We're nearly there! Move it!
快!
Come on!
哦  天啊
Oh, God!
下一站  通风孔
Next stop, vent shaft.
警察!  手放头上
Armed police! Put your hands above your head!
-不准动  警告!  不准动  -霹雳小组上屋顶
- Do not move. Remain where you are. - SWAT team to the roof.
霹雳小组上屋顶
SWAT team to the roof.
快走
Let's go, let's go!
快
Move, move, move!
现在不逃  没机会了
If you can't feel alive now, you never will.
走!
Go!
局长  目标明确  要开枪吗？
Control, we have a clean shot. Do we take it？
-重复  要开枪吗？-不要开枪  听到了吗？
- I repeat, do we take it？- Negative, Team Leader. Negative.
要活捉他们
Do you copy？I want these people alive and kicking.
快!  爬上通风孔
Go! Get up into the shaft!
快啊!
Come on!
现在
Now...
-B计划  转过身  -什么？
- Plan B. Turn around. - What？
转过身
Turn around.
小型降落伞  只适用上升气流
This is a mini-chute. But it only works for the updraft.
我不要自己走  我们一起走
I'm not going without you. We go together.
太重了撑不住
No, no, no, too heavy. We'd drop like stones.
怎么跟你碰面？
So when will I see you again？
明早6点半在普都车站见
Meet me at 6.30am, Pudu train station.
你最好要去  你一定要去
You'd better be there, OK？Promise me you'll be there.
我会去  而且不会迟到  迟到表示我死了
I will be there. I'm never late. If I'm late, it's because I'm dead.
现在
Now,
准备
rip cord.
Ho!
(普杜车站6点33分)
麦克
My God! Mac!
抱歉...你没事吧？
Oh, I'm sorry! I'm sorry. Are you all right？
怎么了？
So what's wrong？
没事  一切都...如期进行
Wrong？Nothing's wrong. Everything is the... way it has to be.
-什么？-珍贝克
- What？- Virginia Baker？
-调查局干员堤贝多  -来吧
- Special Agent Aaron Thibadeaux, FBl. - Come on!
你因窃盗罪被捕
You're under arrest for grand larceny.
你有权保持缄默
You have the right to remain silent...
麦克
Mac？
Mac!
你的话将为呈堂供证
Anything you say can be used against you in a court of law.
麦克  谢了  给你一分钟
Thanks, Mac. You got your one minute.
你是警察
You're a cop.
不
No. Well, not exactly.
不管你信不信堤贝多是调查探员  两年前
Thibadeaux, believe it or not, is FBl. And two years ago
我被他逮到  谈交换条件
he caught me and, uh, cut a deal.
条件是...诱捕你
The deal was that... I had to deliver you.
他们盯上你很久了
They've been onto you for quite a while.
-库斯知道？-才知道
- And Cruz knew, too？- No, he's just found out.
我不明白  何不及早抓我？
I don't get it. Why didn't you pick me up before？
等什么？
What were you waiting for？
起初...想看你的能耐
Well, at first I, uh... well, I wanted to see if you could do it.
鬼扯
Bullshit! Come on!
也想证明我的本事
And I wanted to see if I could do it.
我们不是伙伴？
Weren't we partners？
我不敢相信
I can't believe you'd do this to me.
你最好相信!结束了
Well, you'd better believe it! It's all over.
我交出康瑞  那幅画  面具...
I gave them Greene, the Rembrandt, the mask,
和70亿
and the full seven billion.
怎么是70亿元？
What do you mean, seven？
你只好将就一点
So you'll just have to make do with one, hm？
一分钟到了
I thought you said one minute.
别紧张  他自有分寸
Relax, Hector. He knows what he's doin'.
C计划
Now, plan C.
你的口袋里有护照和钱
In your pocket, you'll find an envelope. A passport, visa, money.
下一步自己看着办
Where you go from here is up to you.
你仍刷新纪录
And you'll still hold the record... alone.
麦克
Mac!
-我不明白  为什么？-相信我...
- I don't understand. Why are you doing this？- Well, believe me,
万全准备就是没料到你
I was prepared for everything, except you.
麦克  时间到了
Mac! Time's up!
跟我走
Come with me.
珍
Gin
你有大好前程
your life, it's all ahead of you.
而我...没戏唱了
Mine... this is all I've got.
不  你有我
No. You've got me.
你有我
You got me.
听仔细  在另一个口袋...
Listen carefully. In your other pocket...
逮捕她
Let's do it.
-过来我就开枪  -大家冷静
- Move and I blow his head off! - Everybody, just be cool.
-通通不准动!  -放下武器
- Nobody move! No-one moves, OK？- Fellas, put your weapons down.
海特  别动!  我会杀了他
You, too, Hector! I'll kill him if you move!
在下一站拦截
We'll get her at the next stop.
麦克  再见
Bye, Mac.
去下一站拦截  快去!
She's headed toward the next station. Move! Move it!
-别开枪  离开这  -快!
- No guns! Get out of here! - Move it! Move it!
老实说...我不知道你们搞什么
You know, I don't know what just went down here,
但调查局绝饶不了你
but I'm gonna see that you're busted outta the Bureau for it.
-麦克  还没结束  -我相信
- It ain't over, Mac. - I believe you.
麦克  交情到此结束
Well, Mac, this looks like the end of a terrible friendship.
你还欠我一回
But you still owe me for today.
有债还债
I always pay my debts.
4个超级芯片原型  各值500万元
Four prototype super chips. Value: five million dollars each.
希望她值得
Hope she was worth it.
她值得
Oh, she was.
再见了
I'll be seein' you, Mac.
不见也罢
I don't think so.
所有人员回月台
OK, Bob, let the people back on the platform.
弄辆车来
Bring me a damn car.
怎么可能？
How did you do it？
在中途跳车  车速减时...
I jumped trains mid-station. When the train slowed down, I just...
-很完美  -现在呢？
- It was perfect. - Was it now？
麦克  其实...我不想独站枝头
You know what, Mac？I don't wanna hold the record alone.
-不？-下个任务要你帮忙
- No？- I need your help on another job.
-要偷王冠？-不  太简单了
- The Crown Jewels or something？- No! Come on, too easy!
我计划...南非有个人
I was thinking of... Well... I know this guy in South Africa.
钻石  钻石  钻石
Diamonds, diamonds, diamonds!
有全世界最大的钻石
The biggest diamonds you'll ever see in your life!
我最爱钻石了
Have I told you how much I love diamonds？
麦克
Mac？
-麦克  -干嘛？
- Mac! - What!
意下如何？
So, what do you think？
-什么？-我的计划
- About what？- About my idea.
可行
It's doable.
-哦  -抱歉...
- Ohh! - Oh, I'm sorry! I'm sorry!